# 哈喽大家好我是王刚
Hello everyone, this is Wang Gang
# 本期视频我跟大家分享
In this video, I'll share the recipe of
# 豆腐煮泥鳅
Pond Loach Stew with Tofu
# 首先我们准备鲜活的泥鳅半斤（250克）
First, get live pond loaches 250g
# 泥鳅不能选择太小否则不好宰杀
Choose loaches that are large enough and easy to process
# 下一步开始处理
Next, prepare loaches for cooking
# 首先将泥鳅放在菜板上
Put loaches on the cutting board
# 然后将泥鳅的头切下来
Then cut the head off
# 由于泥鳅表面黏液较多且比较滑
Since loaches have mucus on their skin and are slippery to hold,
# 同学们切记这一步必须小心操作
be careful when performing this step.
# 切断泥鳅的头之后用菜刀将尾巴压住
After the head comes off, use cleaver knife to hold the tail tightly,
# 然后用手反方向将腹部的内脏挤出来
while squeezing out the internal organs.
# 最后将泥鳅头丢弃不用
Finally, get rid of the head
# 下一步开始准备辅料
Next, prepare the minor ingredients
# 准备老豆腐一小块
Get a small chunk of firm Tofu
# 将豆腐从中间切开之后切成厚片备用
Cut it in half and into thick slices
# 准备生姜一小块切成姜片备用
Get a small piece of ginger and cut into slices
# 准备小葱几根切成葱花备用
Get several scallions and finely chop them
# 将切好的葱花放入盆中下一步开始制作
Put green onions into a bowl and start cooking
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First, heat up the wok
# 锅烧热之后加入适量的底油
When the wok heats up, add proper amount of base oil
# 油温6成热之后在锅中加入一勺食用盐
When the oil reaches 180°C, add a spoonful of salt
# 然后将处理好的泥鳅下锅煎3分钟
Then fry loaches for 3 minutes
# 同学们煎泥鳅的时候最好用锅盖挡住锅面
It's better to put a lid over the wok when frying
# 这样可以防止热油溅出伤人
to protect yourself from hot splashing oil.
# 中途将泥鳅翻面煎香煎黄
Flip loaches over midway and fry until golden
# 锅中再加入姜片爆香
Then add ginger slices to bring out the flavour
# 三分钟之后再加入适量的热水
3 minutes later, fill in proper amount of hot water
# 再加入切好的豆腐下锅
And put Tofu into the wok
# 然后开大火烧开
Turn to high heat and heat to a boil
# 大火烧开之后转中火煮5分钟
Then switch to medium heat and boil for 5 minutes
# 这一步的目的是把汤煮至浓白
This step turns the soup to a milky white color
# 五分钟之后开始调味
5 minutes later, add in seasoning:
# 锅中加入食用盐一勺
A spoon of salt
# 加入胡椒粉半勺
And half a spoon of black pepper powder
# 调好味之后即可出锅上菜
After seasoning, pour out the soup and serve
# 一道营养丰富的豆腐煮泥鳅就制作完成
A nutritious Pond Loach Stew with Tofu is prepared!
# 下面开始技术总结
Now, the technical tips:
# 第一，泥鳅最好现杀现做以保证汤鲜味美
First, it's better to use live loaches for a perfect and umami soup
# 第二，泥鳅的表面黏液比较多，宰杀的时候需要注意安全，嫌麻烦的同学可以交给摊主来处理
Second, loaches are covered in mucus. Be careful when handling yourself or simply let the shop do it for you
# 第三，此菜适合工作压力大的人群食用，具有一定的养生功能
Thrid, this dish is best suited for people under high stress as it's healthy and replenishing
# 豆腐煮泥鳅的技术总结完毕
These are the tips for making Pond Loach Stew with Tofu